well welcome back it's good it's good to
欢迎回来，这很好
see you we want to move on and talk
看到你我们想要继续前进和谈话
about the issue of gathering data
关于收集数据的问题
discerning the problems biblically we
我们以圣经的方式辨别问题
actually have an awful lot of material
实际上有很多材料
to cover in a short amount of time so
在很短的时间内完成
let's get at it and keep your Bible
让我们来看看并保留你的圣经
handy I think one of the most common
方便我觉得最常见的一个
problems that a lot of councillors face
问题，很多议员的脸
when they start counseling is the fact
当他们开始咨询是事实
that they don't carefully listen to
他们不仔细听
where a council Lee is coming from they
理事会李来自他们
think they know the problem in fact a
认为他们实际上知道这个问题了
few years ago I had a good friend of
几年前，我有一个好朋友
mine who is an associate pastor of a
我是谁的副牧师
rather large church and there was a
相当大的教堂，有一个
couple in their church that had some
夫妻俩在他们的教堂里有一些
fairly serious marital issues and
相当严重的婚姻问题和
problems that came for counseling and
该来的咨询问题和
the senior pastor of the church is a
教会的高级牧师是
well-known guy and and he came in and
众所周知的家伙和他进来了
wanted to be a part of that counseling
想成为咨询的一部分
which was really good and so they sent
这真的很好，所以他们发送
down had prayer they said what seems to
他们说了什么似乎是祈祷
be the problem and the husband and wife
是问题和丈夫和妻子
shared a little bit of their problem
分享了他们的一些问题
then the pastor said listen I want both
然后牧师说听我想要两个
of you to take your Bible and let's go
你拿走圣经然后走了
over to Ephesians chapter 5 and so he
到了以弗所书第5章，所以他
took him over to Ephesians 5 and he the
把他带到以弗所书5章，然后他
pastor then proceeded to preach right
然后牧师继续讲道
through Ephesians chapter 5 and after
通过以弗所书第5章及之后
about 45 minutes of explaining that
约45分钟的解释
particular passage which my friend the
我朋友的特别段落
associate pastor said man he did a great
副牧师说男人他做得很棒
job he explained exactly what that
他完全解释了那个问题
passage was teaching and it was just
通道是教学，它只是
fantastic
奇妙
he ended the thing by saying now that's
他结束了这件事现在就说了
what you need to do let's close in
你需要做什么让我们接近
prayer and so they closed in prayer and
祈祷，所以他们在祷告和结束时关闭
the senior pastor got up and walked out
高级牧师起身走了出去
and that couple was just sitting there
那对夫妇只是坐在那里
and so my friends started asking a few
所以我的朋友们开始问几句
more questions about what was going on
关于 发生 了什么更多的问题
in their marriage and pretty soon what
在他们的婚姻和很快很快
unfolded was completely different than
展开完全不同于
what the senior pastor had assumed even
高级牧师甚至假设的是什么
though he taught the Word of God
虽然他教导了神的话语
correctly
正确地
he totally missed their problem and a
他完全错过了他们的问题和一个
lot of new counselors will do that
很多新的辅导员会做
frequently they'll assume that they know
经常他们会认为他们知道
what's going on but they'll not ask any
发生了什么，但他们不会问任何问题
questions I want you to take your Bible
问题我希望你带上你的圣经
for a moment and let's go over to the
一会儿，让我们去到的
book of Proverbs we want to go to
我们想去的箴言书
proverbs chapter 18 and verse 13 I want
谚语第18章和第13节我想要
you to think about this for a moment
你想一下这一点
proverbs chapter 18 and verse 13 he who
谚语第18章和第13节他是谁
gives an answer before he hears it is
在他听到之前给出答案
folly and ashamed to him in other words
换句话说，愚蠢和羞愧
there are an awful lot of very foolish
有很多非常愚蠢的事情
counselors who mean well and they have
辅导员，他们的意思很好，他们有
very good intentions but they don't
非常好的意图，但他们没有
listen to where people are coming from
倾听人们的来源
the people that you will be counseling
人们，你会辅导
are either struggling with personal sin
要么与个人的罪恶斗争
in their life or they're suffering as a
在他们的生活和他们的痛苦作为
result of sin or maybe it's the sin of
罪的结果或者也许是罪的结果
other people suffering and sin suffering
其他人痛苦和罪恶的痛苦
in sin it goes one of those two things
在罪中它是这两件事之一
and the Bible either brings help and
圣经要么带来帮助，要么
healing to those who are suffering or it
愈合那些谁是患有或它
brings a way to really change and grow
带来真正改变和成长的方法
for those who are participating in sin
对于那些参与犯罪的人
but we've got to find out what is it
但我们必须找出它是什么
exactly that's going on in their life
这正是他们生活中的事情
now let me illustrate this for you if I
如果我，现在让我为你说明一下
can by asking the question why is it
可以问这个问题，为什么是它
important for us to gather data well to
对于我们很好地收集数据很重要
answer this first of all you need to
首先回答你需要的
take your Bibles and go over to first
拿走你的圣经然后先去看看
Thessalonians chapter 5 and verse 14
帖撒罗尼迦书第5章和 第14节
here the Apostle Paul talks about his
在这里使徒保罗谈论他的
own personal ministry and he admonishes
自己的个人事工，他劝告
the church there at Thessalonica he says
他说，塞萨洛尼卡那里的教堂
we urge you brethren admonished the
我们敦促弟兄们告诫你们
unruly encouraged the faint-hearted
不守规矩地鼓励胆小的人
help the weak be patient
帮助弱者耐心等待
with everyone now the reason why it's
现在每个人都有这个原因
important to gather data is because what
收集数据很重要是因为什么
are we dealing with are we dealing with
我们正在处理的是我们正在处理的问题
someone who is unruly if if that's true
如果那是真的，那就是不守规矩的人
then they need admonishment and by the
然后他们需要训诫和
way that's our word that we talked about
这就是我们谈到的话
in our earlier sessions new fatale to
在我们早些时候的会议上新的美国人
warn to admonish to counsel is the way
警告劝告律师是道路
that that word is translated we urge you
那个词被翻译了，我们恳请你
brethren to admonish the unruly but
弟兄们劝告不守规矩但是
maybe they're not unruly maybe they're
也许他们不是不守规矩也许他们是
faint-hearted well if that's the case
胆小的人好，如果是这样的话
then we need to encourage them they
那么，我们需要鼓励他们，他们
don't need admonishment they need an
不需要他们需要的警告
encouragement or maybe you're dealing
鼓励或者你正在交易
with someone who's weak and in this
和一个软弱的人在一起
particular case that person needs help
这个人需要帮助的特殊情况
so you you've got to know where your
所以你必须知道你的位置
counsel T is coming from before you know
律师T在您知道之前来自
how to counsel them properly what do
如何正确地为他们提供建议
they need to they need courage Minh do
他们需要他们需要勇气Minh做
they need admonishment do they need help
他们需要警告，他们需要帮助吗？
which one are we talking about which
我们在谈论哪一个
brings us to another issue we can see
把我们带到另一个我们可以看到的问题
Jesus illustrating this in his own
耶稣用自己的方式说明这一点
ministry in his own life in fact his own
在他自己的生活事工其实是他自己的
personal counseling John chapter 3 we've
个人辅导约翰福音第3章我们已经
got Nicodemus there Jesus is being
耶稣正在那里得到尼哥底母
rather confrontive with that particular
相当具有特殊性
man why is he that way well because if
男人为什么他那么好，因为如果
you go back to John chapter 3 and you
你回到约翰福音第3章和你
take a look at verse 1 he was a ruler of
看看第一节他的统治者
the Jews he was a man of the pharisees
犹太人，他是法利赛人的人
and jesus is pretty strong with him
和耶稣相处得很好
pretty straightforward with them and in
他们和他们相当直接
fact shocks him by what he has to say
事实让他震惊的是他所说的话
and even uses the illustration of that
甚至使用那个例子
you have to be reborn again and or born
你必须要再次重生和或诞生
again and then the man asks well is that
然后男人问得那么好
possible how in the world can I do that
我可以在世界上如何做到这一点
I can't crawl back into my mother's womb
我无法爬回母亲的子宫里
and of course Jesus wasn't talking about
当然，耶稣并没有谈论
physical rebirth
身体重生
he was talking about spiritual rebirth
他在谈论精神重生
what is born of the spirit is a spirit
什么是天生的精神 ，是一种精神
there in verse six so he's very
在第六节，所以他非常
confronted there but when you go over to
在那里遇到但是当你走过去的时候
John chapter four then you have the
约翰四章然后你有了
woman of Samaria and this is different
撒马利亚的女人，这是不同的
as a Samaritan woman she knew that Jesus
作为一个撒玛利亚妇女， 她知道耶稣
being a Jew looked down upon her because
作为一个犹太人看不起她，因为
she was a half-breed
她是一个混血儿
she knew that and so Jesus is much more
她知道这一点， 耶稣也是如此
gentle with her and much more caring
对她温柔，更有爱心
with her than he is with Nicodemus who's
和她在一起，而不是与尼哥德慕在一起
a Pharisee and a ruler the Jews so who
一个法利赛人和一个统治者犹太人如此
are we dealing with now if you don't
我们现在 处理的，如果你不
gather good data you don't know who
收集你不知道谁的好数据
you're dealing with that's the problem
你在处理这就是问题所在
and certainly we do not want to be
当然我们不想成为
accused of being one of the leadership
被指为领导的一个
of Israel like we see in Jeremiah
我们在耶利米看到的以色列
chapter 6 and verse 14 where it talks
第6章和第14节在那里 会谈
about the priests of Israel and the
关于以色列和以色列的祭司
religious leaders it says they have
它说他们有宗教领袖
healed the brokenness of my people
治愈了我的人民的破碎
superficially saying peace peace but
表面上说和平和平但是
there is no peace we don't want to do
我们不想做任何和平
that as counselors we want we don't want
作为我们想要的辅导员，我们不想要
to heal the brokenness of people in a
治愈一个人的破碎
superficial manner we don't want to put
我们不想表面的态度
band-aids on cancer we want to get at
我们希望得到癌症的创可贴
the root cause right we want to get at
我们想要得到的根本原因
it and oftentimes on some of the surface
它经常出现在某些表面上
it's in the heart
它在心里
let's go over to proverbs chapter 20
让我们回到第20章的谚语
proverbs chapter 20 and we're interested
谚语第20章， 我们感兴趣
in verse 5 proverbs chapter 20 and verse
在第5节箴言第20章和经文中
5 notice what Solomon says here in
5 注意所罗门在这里说的话
regards to the heart he says a plan or
他心里有一个计划或者说
we could translate this purpose or even
我们可以翻译这个目的甚至
intention here with the Hebrew term a
这里的意图是希伯来语a
plan or the purpose or intention of a
计划或目的或意图
man is like deep water but a man or in
男人就像深水， 但是男人还是男人
the heart of man a planner of purpose in
人的心脏是一个有目的的计划者
the heart of man it's like deep water
人的心脏就像深水
but a man of understanding draws it out
但是一个理解的人会把它拉出来
so these are deep issues that are
所以这些都是深刻的问题
underneath the surface and oftentimes it
在表面下面，经常是它
takes an awful lot of data gathering
收集了大量的数据
we're not talking about something that's
我们不是在谈论那些事情
buried in a person's subconscious we're
埋藏在一个人的潜意识中我们是
not talking about that we're not going
不是说我们不去
into archeological digs into the
到考古发掘 进入
unconscious in fact nowhere in the bible
事实上，无意识在圣经中无处可去
does it ever say that man has a
它有没有说人类有一个
subconscious from a biblical point of
从圣经的角度看潜意识
view and from a scientific point of view
查看并从科学 的角度来看
a subconscious makes absolutely no sense
潜意识绝对没有意义
there is no such thing as a subconscious
没有潜意识这样的东西
the bible doesn't establish it biblical
圣经没有建立圣经
anthropology doesn't establish this
人类学并没有建立这一点
science doesn't establish it it's an
科学没有建立它是一个
assumption and it's actually a Freudian
假设它实际上是弗洛伊德式的
assumption that was later on passed down
后来传承下来的假设
through a lot of Neo Freudians Carl
通过很多新弗洛伊德人卡尔
Gustav Jung where somehow buried in
Gustav Jung 在某处埋葬了
you're out of awareness mind deep in the
你已经脱离了意识深处了
subconscious of your life is the reason
你的生命潜意识就是原因
why you're having the problems why
你为什么遇到问题的原因
you're having and only a trained
你有，只有训练有素
psychotherapist can peel back the layers
心理治疗师可以剥离层
of consciousness and get down to that
意识到了
particular problem that make turns
转弯的特殊问题
counselling into a real Gnostic system
咨询真正的诺斯替教系统
where only people who are trained in
只有受过训练的人才
psychotherapy can somehow get to the
心理治疗可以以某种方式获取到
core issues of a person's problem buried
埋葬一个人问题的核心问题
deep deep down inside a person's
在一个人的内心深处
subconscious well there's a there's a
潜意识很好，有一个
biblical word for that baloney that is
那个巴洛尼的圣经词是
just absolutely baloney it's nonsense
只是绝对的胡扯这是胡说八道
now the Bible talks about consciousness
现在圣经谈论意识
the Bible talks about unconsciousness
圣经谈论无意识
but there is no such thing as this this
但因为这本没有这样的事
out of awareness domain within a person
超出一个人的意识领域
the psyche or whatever you want to call
无论你要拨打的心理或
it that somehow is buried down there and
它以某种方式被埋在那里，
this is why a lot of these Freudians and
这就是为什么很多这些弗洛伊德人和
neuro Freudians that came out of modern
从现代出来的神经弗洛伊德人
psychology are often referred to in the
心理学常被提及
history of psychology as irrational
心理学史不合理
psychologists irrational why are they
心理学家不理智他们为什么
called the irrational psychologists
称为非理性心理学家
because no amount of rationality is ever
因为没有多少合理性
going to be
将会是
we'll do in a psychic archeological way
我们将以心理学的考古方式进行
dig down into no amount of rationales
深入研究没有多少理由
gonna be able to dig down into the out
要能够向下挖掘到了
of awareness mind you can't do it and so
意识到你不能做到这一点
they got to use enigmatic ways in order
他们必须按顺序使用神秘的方法
to bring these things to the surface
把这些东西带到表面
like what what are we talking about
喜欢我们在说什么
we're talking about hypnosis or dream
我们在谈论催眠或梦想
analysis you know Freudian Freud's
分析你知道弗洛伊德弗洛伊德的
famous analyzing of dreams in fact it's
着名的梦想分析实际上就是这样
very interesting that Freud and his
弗洛伊德和他的非常有趣
protege Jung back in the early 1900s
在20世纪初，Jung回归
one day were analyzing each other in
有一天在互相分析
each other's dreams and Freud got so mad
彼此的梦想和弗洛伊德都很生气
at you about his analyzing of his dreams
在你的分析他的梦想
that he walked out on Neumann they never
他从未走过诺伊曼
spoke to each other rest of the their
交谈的对方休息的他们
time and he just got so angry and and
时间和他只是非常气愤和和
young and in actually developing off of
年轻，实际上正在发展
Freud system his own little system and
弗洛伊德系统他自己的小系统和
his own little view in fact he added the
他自己的一点看法实际上他补充说
concept of collective consciousness or a
集体意识或 概念
collective unconsciousness as a part of
集体无意识作为一部分
man well Freud understood even back when
男人好弗洛伊德甚至回想起来的时候
he developed the idea of the
他开发的想法
subconscious he understood back during
潜意识里他明白了
that particular time that that the word
那个特定时间那个词
subconscious was a bad term so he didn't
潜意识是一个坏词，所以他没有
even like to use the term he would
甚至喜欢用他会说的那个词
rather use the term unconsciousness but
而是使用“ 无意识 ” 一词
nevertheless as time went on people used
尽管如此，随着时间的推移人们使用了
the term more frequently and then it
这个词更频繁，然后它
became known primarily as the
成为主要被称为
subconscious well the subconscious from
潜意识下潜意识
a biblical standpoint does not exist so
圣经的角度看不存在，因此
that rules out a good deal of
这排除了一个很好的 协议
psychotherapy this is one of the reasons
心理治疗这是其中一个原因
why in biblical counseling most
为什么在圣经咨询中最多
difficult counselors who want to trade
想要交易的困难顾问
stay true to biblical theology cannot
坚持圣经神学不能
endorse people like Larry Crabbe
支持Larry Crabbe这样的人
Larry Crabb is a Christian form of Neil
拉里·克拉布是尼尔的基督徒形象
Freudianism in fact in his book inside
弗洛伊德主义实际上在他的书里面
out he talks about the iceberg principle
他谈到了冰山原则
and he talks about that which is part of
他谈到了那部分内容
your conscious awareness and then deep
你有意识的意识，然后深刻
down buried in your unconscious is it
埋没在你的无意识中是它
like an iceberg that's the real reason
就像冰山一样，这才是真正的原因
for all your problems and you're out of
为了你所有的问题而你已经离开了
awareness mind that's not true
意识到这不是真的
that is that a good theology would never
那是一个好神学永远不会
ever establish that from Scripture that
永远从圣经中确立那个
doesn't exist
不存在
that's a Freudian system superimposed on
这是一个叠加在上面的弗洛伊德系统
top of biblical theology but it's not
圣经神学的顶部，但事实并非如此
what biblical theology is teaching we
圣经神学在教我们什么
have to reverse that and allow our
必须扭转这种局面并允许我们的
biblical theology to run our counseling
圣经神学来进行我们的咨询
theory that's what has to happen what is
理论是什么必须发生的事情
it about man so we've got to get rid of
关于男人所以我们必须摆脱它
that kind of thinking and it was Freud
这种想法，这是弗洛伊德
in connection with that that also talked
与那些也谈过的人有关
about the concept of mental illness now
现在关于精神疾病的概念
fasten your seat belt and put your crash
系好安全带，让你的车祸
helmets on are you ready are you ready I
安全帽你准备好了，你准备好了吗我
know it's early in the morning take a
知道这是在早上采取早
good swig of your coffee right now oh
现在好喝的咖啡哦
you're not allowed to have it in here
你不能在这里拥有它
sorry about that that was just a test we
对不起，那只是我们的考验
have ushers in the back was gonna come
后面有迎来者会来
and get you if you did that all right
并得到你，如果你这样做 没事
there is no such thing as mental illness
没有精神疾病这样的事情
think about it think about the term
想一想这个词
mental illness never in the history of
精神疾病永远不会在历史上
the planet has there ever been mental
这个星球曾经有过精神
illness because it's impossible for the
疾病，因为它是不可能的
mind to get ill your brain can get ill
生病你的大脑会生病
you can have a tumor on the brain you
你可以对大脑有你一个肿瘤
can have an aneurysm in your brain you
你脑中可以有动脉瘤
can have significant trauma to your
可能会给你带来很大的创伤
brain but your brain will have damage to
大脑， 但你的大脑会受到伤害
it but your mind cannot it's impossible
它但你的思想不可能是不可能的
because the mind is a nonentity
因为头脑是一个无足轻重的人
sometimes I say I teach the intro to
有时我说我教的介绍到
psych class at the Masters College and I
我和硕士学院的心理课
talked to students in the early weeks of
在最初几周与学生交谈
that intro to psych class I said when a
那个介绍心理课我说的时候
person's brain-dead do they stop
他们的脑死了他们会停止
thinking well most students are sitting
大多数学生都在思考
there oh yeah yeah really well you're
还有哦，是啊是啊真的很好你
thinking like a
想着像
a materialist you're thinking like a
一个你正在思考的唯物主义者
atheist when a person's brain-dead they
无神论者，当一个人的脑子死了他们
don't stop thinking because they still
不要停止思考，因为他们仍然
have a mind you can be brainless but not
有一个心灵， 你可以无脑但没有
mindless how do we know that second
我们怎么知道第二个
corinthians 5:9 talks about whether i'm
哥林多后书5： 我是否是 9轮会谈
president in the body or absent to the
总统在体内或不存在的
body i make it my goal to please him so
身体我的目标是取悦他
the soul has intentionality even without
即使没有，灵魂也有意向性
a brain it has the capacity to be able
大脑它必须 能够在容量
to think and purpose and please God and
思考和目的，取悦上帝和
glorify Him when a person's brain dead
当一个人的大脑死亡时，荣耀他
doesn't mean that they're mindless
并不意味着他们是盲目
doesn't mean that at all so if we're
并不意味着如果我们这样做的话
really thinking according to what the
真的按照什么思考
Scriptures have to say here then we're
经文必须在这里说，然后我们就是
thinking that the mind cannot get ill
以为心灵不会生病
the brain can there can be brain
大脑可以有大脑
illnesses there can be chemical problems
疾病可能存在化学问题
in the brain but the mind cannot get ill
在大脑中， 但心灵不能生病
now as long as the mind is in connection
现在，只要心灵在联系
with the body one has an impact upon the
与身体一个具有后的影响
other so if you suffer damage it can
其他所以，如果你遭受损害它可以
affect your thinking in your mind to the
影响你的思维在你的心中的
brain or if you have if you're
大脑，或者如果你有的话
discouraged for a long enough period of
气馁了足够长的时间
time and you're really depressed that
时间和你真的很沮丧
will repressed your immune system and
会抑制你的免疫系统
discourage and severely depressed people
劝阻和严重抑郁的人
that are chronically depressed tend to
长期抑郁的人倾向于
be subject to more illnesses more
受到更多的疾病
disease we know that statistically so if
疾病， 我们知道统计上如此
your mind can affect your body and how
你的思想会影响你的身体和方式
your body performs why is it in Haiti
你的身体表现为什么它在海地
and Sciences demonstrating this over and
和科学证明了这一点
over again that witch doctors put a
女巫医生再说一遍
curse on people and they die why do they
诅咒人，他们死了为什么他们
do that because those people believe
这样做是因为那些人​​相信
they're gonna die
他们会死的
the witch doctor can put a curse on
巫医可以诅咒
somebody doesn't believe in voodoo and
有人不相信巫术和
they don't die but if you believe in
他们不会死， 但如果你相信
voodoo you die that shows you how our
voodoo你死了，告诉你我们是怎样的
belief system or how our mind are in
信仰体系或我们的思想如何
material intangible mind has an effect
物质无形的心灵有影响
upon the body most medical doctors and
在身体上大多数医生和
physicians understand that they talk
医生明白他们说话
about it in first-year medical textbooks
在第一年的医学教科书中
they talk about the fact that
他们谈论的事实
if the patient believes in you and
如果病人相信你和
believes in the medication that it has a
相信它有一种药物
30% greater chance of working if it that
如果这样的话， 工作机会增加 30％
if they don't then you lose that 30% why
如果他们不这样做，你会失去30％的原因
is it that the American the Journal of
难道是美国 的杂志
the American Medical Association back a
美国医学会回来了
few years ago published a whole series
几年前发表了一整套系列
of articles on placebos and
关于安慰剂和安息日的文章
antidepressants in fact you can look it
抗抑郁药，其实你可以看看它
up it's called the st. John's wort study
它被称为st。约翰的麦汁研究
where they evaluated Zoloft
在那里他们评估Zoloft
st. John's wort and placebos and they
ST。约翰的麦汁和安慰剂和他们
determined that all of them placebos is
确定所有这些安慰剂都是
just a sugar pill or pill with inert
只是一个糖丸或惰性药丸
ingredients in it all three of them have
其中三种成分都有
an equal ability to solve depression
解决抑郁症的能力相等
Soloff st. John wort is just kind of the
Soloffst。约翰麦汁只是一种
natural remedy supposedly for depression
据说是抑郁症的自然疗法
but there was very little statistical
但是统计数据很少
difference between zoloft very expensive
zoloft之间的区别非常昂贵
antidepressant st. John wort and placebo
抗抑郁药圣。约翰麦汁和安慰剂
very little difference between those two
这两者之间差别不大
statistically you can look it up
从统计上来说，你可以查一查
yourself the British Medical Society
你自己是英国医学会
after that was published published their
之后发表了他们的出版物
own research and came to the same
自己的研究也来了
conclusion the Canadian Medical
结论加拿大医学
Association did the same thing and they
协会做了同样的事情和他们
came to the same conclusion that placebo
得出了与安慰剂相同的结论
if you believe so what is it what is
如果你认为是什么呢是什么
that what is that little drug it's hope
这是什么小毒品是希望
in a bottle form if I believe I'm gonna
如果我相信我会以瓶子的形式出现
die if I really believe it I'll probably
如果我真的相信它我会死的
die the mind has a huge effect upon the
死心中有于产生巨大影响
body huge effect and the body has a huge
身体巨大的效果和身体有巨大的
effect upon the mind you can be in an
你可以在心中产生影响
accident put your head through
事故让你头脑发热
windshield of the car and that'll affect
汽车挡风玻璃 那会影响
the way you think you're not going to be
你认为你不会 是这样
able to think as clearly as long as the
只要能够清楚地思考
two are in connection with each other
两个是彼此连接
both have an impact upon each other both
两者都相互影响
than do but then once the mind the
比起来，但一旦心灵了
body's dead and the mine is separated
尸体死了，矿井分开了
from the body the mind still has the
从身体的头脑仍然有
capacity to be able to think intend and
能够思考意图的能力
purpose so when you're gathering data
目的所以当你收集数据时
you've got to get to know your counselor
你必须了解你的顾问
right you have to do that what's really
对，你必须这样做才是真的
going on in their life what's going on
在他们的生活中继续发生着什么
deep down under the surface not in we're
在我们面前的表面深处
not talking about the subconscious we're
不是说我们的潜意识
not talking about trying to find out
不谈论试图找出
whether they have some mental illness
他们是否有精神疾病
which really doesn't exist it either is
它真的不存在它
a spiritual issue or a physical issue
精神问题或身体问题
there's no halfway between those two
这两者之间没有中途
it's a spiritual issue or a physical
这是一个精神问题或身体问题
issue now one can affect the other one
问题现在可以影响另一个
can play off of the other but there's no
可以玩另一个，但没有
such thing as a mental illness now what
像精神病这样的东西现在是什么
kind of data then do you gather well
那种数据然后你收集得好
with that in mind then you've got to
考虑到这一点，那么你必须这样做
gather physical data what are the sleep
收集物理数据什么是睡眠
patterns medications diet activity level
模式药物饮食活动水平
illnesses several years ago as a pastor
几年前作为牧师的疾病
I had an older couple that was a member
我有一对老夫妇是会员
of our church I'll never forget them
我们教会永远不会忘记他们
Delbert and Evelyn Lakes God has since
从那时起，德尔伯特和伊芙琳湖就是上帝
promoted them to heaven what a sweet
把他们推向天堂真是太甜蜜了
sweet couple one day I got a call from
甜蜜的情侣有一天我接到了电话
Evelyn and said pastor I got to see you
伊芙琳和牧师说我见到了你
I am suffering depression I've never
我正在遭受抑郁症，我从来没有
suffered from depression ever in my life
在我的生命中遭受过抑郁症
before ever I have terrible depression I
在此之前，我有可怕的抑郁症
think it's almost demonic and I said
认为这几乎是恶魔，我说
Evelyn let's get together and talk so
伊芙琳让我们聚在一起谈谈
she and Delbert came in we sat down
她和Delbert进来我们坐了下来
there in my office at the church and I
在我 教堂的办公室和我
asked her a lot of questions to find out
问了她很多问题，找出
what was going on in her life and and
生活和生活中发生了什么
one of the things that she mentioned was
她提到的一件事就是
I wanted to know all the medications
我想知道所有的药物
that she was on and she listed her
她在，她列出了她
medications as an elderly person and one
作为老年人和一个人的药物
of them was a beta blocker so between
他们是β受体阻滞剂所以之间
that particular time
那个特定的时间
the the next time that she came into
在她 进入了下一次
counseling I always have a PDR
咨询我总是有PDR
physicians Desk Reference or either
医生服务台参考或任何一个
either that or one of the nurses boiled
无论是那个还是其中一个护士都煮了
down version kind of like the nurses one
下来的版本就像护士一样
since I'm not a trained medical doctor
因为我不是一名训练有素的医生
so you look up the side effects of those
所以你要查看那些副作用
medications and that particular diet of
药物和特殊饮食
beta blocker at the top of the side
顶部的β阻滞剂
effects is severe depression whoa so I
效果是严重的抑郁症，所以我
called up Evelyn I said Haviland I said
叫伊夫林我说哈维兰我说过
when did you start experiencing this
你什么时候开始体验这个
depression she said well about two two
抑郁症她说得好两个左右
months ago I said when did your
几个月前我说过你的时间
cardiologist put you on this beta
心脏病专家为您提供此测试版
blocker well it's about two and a half
阻止它大约两个半
months ago said you know that one of the
几个月前说你知道其中的一个
side effects of this medication is
这种药物的副作用是
severe depression No so I think you need
严重抑郁症不，所以我认为你需要
to call your cardiologist and ask him if
给你的心脏病专家打电话问他是否
you could be put on a different drug
你可以戴上不同的药物
okay so she called the doctor doctors oh
好吧所以她给医生打电话哦
sure
当然
switch drugs she was fine now I could
切换药物她现在我很好
have spent weeks with that lady thinking
已经花了几个星期与 夫人思维
there was a spiritual problem or some
有一个精神问题或一些
kind of demonic oppression but it wasn't
一种恶魔般的压迫， 但事实并非如此
it was a drug that was going on so when
这是这是怎么回事，这样当药物
you're getting to know your counselor
你要知道你的辅导员
you've got to find out what's happening
你必须弄清楚发生了什么
what's going on in their life what are
这是怎么回事在他们的生活是什么
they taking what are the medications
他们服用什么药物
what are their sleep problems lack of
他们有什么睡眠问题缺乏
sleep has and lucinda genic effects upon
睡眠有并 在辛达核不影响
people they start imagining things that
人们开始想象那些东西
aren't true if you haven't slept well I
如果你睡不好我不是真的
live in a college environment I'm around
生活在大学的环境中我就在身边
people that are walking zombies all
所有人都在走僵尸
right they don't sleep well and they're
对， 他们睡不好，他们是
sitting there in class you know drinking
坐在课堂上，你知道喝酒
coffee all the time so physical patterns
咖啡一直都是这样的物理模式
what are resources and relationships job
什么是资源和关系工作
situations school intellectual social
情境学校知识社会
spiritual what's going on in their life
精神在他们的生活中发生了什么
their emotions feelings are they feeling
他们的情感感受是他们的感受
oriented action
导向行动
their behavior sins of commission and
他们的行为罪和佣金罪
omission conceptual how do they think
遗漏概念他们如何思考
what are their goals what are their
他们的目标是什么？
values what are their desires what are
价值观是什么他们的愿望是什么
their motives one of the best ways I
他们的动机是我最好的方式之一
like to determine person's goals is ask
喜欢确定人的目标是问
them let me see or your at least than
他们让我看到或至少你
what they value let me see your
他们重视的是让我看到你的
checkbook that tells me what they value
支票簿，告诉我他们的价值
in life let me see your checkbook
在生活中让我看你的支票簿
historical good and bad past context
历史的好坏过去的背景
present context failures school job
目前的背景失败学校工作
problems that little cross stick preach
小交叉传播的问题
just helps you to remember all the
只是帮助你记住所有的
things I need to examine physical
我需要检查物理的东西
resources relationships emotions actions
资源关系情绪行动
conceptual historical background I want
我想要的概念历史背景
to collect as much data I want to get to
收集我想要的 数据
know that person really well so much so
知道的人真的很好以至于
that when my council Lee leaves that
当我的理事会李离开时
they think to themselves now he knows me
他们现在认为自己了解我
he knows me now how do you do that how
他知道我现在该怎么做，你该怎么办
do you gather data well one way and this
你是否以某种方式 收集数据？
is very helpful is by using a personal
非常有帮助的是使用个人
data inventory this is a more formal way
数据库存这是一种更正式的方式
most the time when I do counseling I ask
大多数 时候我辅导我问 的时候
a person even if I know them pretty well
一个人，即使我非常了解他们
did just to fill it out because over the
也只是因为填充它出过
years it's just something that has been
几年来，它只是一直存在的事情
developed by biblical counselors to
由圣经辅导员开发
collect a lot of basic information real
收集很多真实 的基本信息
quickly so you can get started and
很快，所以你可以开始和
actually move the counseling on a little
实际上有点推荐咨询
bit quicker it asks a lot of key
它要快一点，问了很多关键
questions and if you want to see an
问题，如果你想看到一个
example of that then get a hold of Jay
然后举例说明杰伊
Adams book competent to counsel or the
亚当斯的书可以胜任律师或者
Christian counselors manual the
基督徒辅导员手册
Christian counselors man is in the back
基督徒辅导员男子在后面
of both of those books is a sample of
这两本书的样本都是
PDI
also you need to ask the proper kind of
你也需要问一下这种
questions some of those questions are
其中一些问题是问题
going to be extensive and some of those
将是广泛的和其中一些
questions are going to be intensive
问题将是密集的
extensive is sort of like the shotgun
广泛有点像霰弹枪
technique shotgun shoots
技术猎枪射击
instead of shooting a bullet it actually
而不是实际射击子弹
shoots pellets that spread over a large
拍摄的颗粒饲料，分散在很大
area so you want to ask questions about
所以你要问的问题区域
a large area of their life in other
在他人的大部分生活中
words extensive question asks a little
广泛的问题请问一点
about a lot intensive questions is
关于很多密集的问题是
picking up a rifle and often take that
拿起步枪，并经常 采取
rifle and aim at specific areas of their
步枪，瞄准他们的特定区域
life that seem to be a particular
生活似乎是一个特别的
problem areas so first you start broad
问题领域所以首先你开始广泛
asking questions all over their life
在他们的生活中提出问题
their relationships here and there
他们在这里和那里的关系
because people like to think that they
因为人们喜欢认为他们
can compartmentalize their problems but
可以划分他们的问题但是
in reality those particular problems
实际上那些特殊的问题
have an effect upon how they function in
对它们的作用产生影响
their marriage how they function with
他们的婚姻如何运作
their kids how they function at church
他们的孩子他们如何在教堂工作
how they function on the job how they
他们如何在工作中发挥作用
spend their money all of these things
把钱花在所有这些东西上
become a key thing and then once you've
成为关键的事情，然后一旦你
asked these extensive questions you've
问你这些广泛的问题
highlighted areas that you want to go
突出显示您想要去的区域
back to and ask more intensive questions
回到并提出更多密集的问题
about so you're starting broad but
所以你开始广泛但是
you're working towards more of a focused
你正朝着更加专注的方向努力
idea starting broad and working towards
想法开始广泛，努力
a more focused data gathering and then
然后是一个更集中的数据收集
of course it's vitally important as well
当然， 这也是至关重要的
that you ask questions that are relevant
你提出相关的问题
relevant and the more you ask extensive
相关的，你问得越广泛
questions the more you're able to ask
质疑你能提出的问题越多
relevant questions what do we mean by
相关问题我们的意思是什么
that you've got to be focused and
那你一定要集中，并
purposeful to what will help you to
有目的地帮助你
determine the route issues
确定的路线问题
focused and purposeful - what will help
专注和有目的- 什么会有所帮助
you determine the route issues that's
你确定了路线问题
what we're talking about then you need
我们在谈论，那么你需要什么
to ask questions that find facts ask
提出发现事实的问题
questions like what how where when what
问题是什么时候怎么样
for how often
多久一次
all of those are critical a good
所有这些都是至关重要的
counselor is like Sherlock Holmes when I
当我的时候，辅导员就像是福尔摩斯
was a boy I read everything that Arthur
是个男孩我读了Arthur的一切
Conan Doyle wrote I loved reading
柯南道尔写道， 我喜欢读书
Sherlock Holmes and all those detective
夏洛克福尔摩斯和所有那些侦探
stories and how observant Sherlock
故事和Sherlock如何观察
Holmes was as a detective and a good
福尔摩斯是一个侦探和一个好人
counselor a good caring Christian
辅导员一个善于关怀的基督徒
counselor is a person who is fastidious
辅导员是一个挑剔的人
they they are able to pick up on little
他们所以能挑上一点
nuances and they see themes of things
细微差别，他们看到事物的主题
that are going on in people's lives they
他们在人们的生活中正在发生这种情况
see that they see how this problem
看到他们看到了这个问题
affects their marriage and how it
影响他们的婚姻和如何
affects their child rearing and how it
影响他们的孩子养育及其如何
affects their job and how it affects how
影响他们的工作以及它如何影响工作
they spend their money they see how
他们花自己的钱，他们怎么看
those problems things that that person
那些人那些问题的事情
themselves has never seen they go whoa I
他们自己从未见过他们去过我
didn't realize that affected me that way
没有意识到那样影响了我
you it's very very difficult to
你真的很难
compartmentalize problems and you your
划分问题和你的问题
questions need to be open and ended in
问题需要公开并结束
other words we want to give the counsel
换句话说我们想给出建议
Lee the opportunity to be able to
李有机会能够
provide as much information from their
从提供尽可能多的信息，他们的
point of view as possible we don't want
尽可能我们不想要的观点
to direct their answers and that
指导他们的答案和
provides flexibility for response it
提供灵活的响应
determines what is important to your
确定对你重要的是什么
counselor it helps your counselor to
辅导员它可以帮助你的辅导员
better understand here's a good example
更好地理解这是一个很好的例子
of this a close question is do you want
这个一个接近的问题是你想要的吗？
to get married I seem to be asking that
结婚我似乎在问这个问题
a lot on a college campus be better to
大学校园里的很多东西都比较好
ask the question what
问问题是什么
your thoughts about marriage so the
你对婚姻的想法如此
close question only asks for a yes or no
关闭问题只询问是或否
type of answer the open question allows
打开的问题允许的答案类型
them to formulate it they have to think
他们要制定它们，他们必须思考
they have to put together a full
他们必须整理好
sentence thought why do they put it
句子以为他们为什么这么说
together that way why do they say it
他们为什么这么说呢？
that way
这样
that tells you about a lot about how
这会告诉你很多关于如何做的事
they think what's really going on in
他们认为真正发生了什么
their mind so you've got to ask
他们的想法让你不得不问
questions that are open-ended questions
问题是开放式问题
and then ask questions that are specific
然后问 是具体问题
avoid fuzzy questions
避免模​​糊的问题
don't settle for vague or general
不要满足于模糊或笼统
answers get your counsel ease out of
答案让你的建议轻松自如
vegs Ville or fuzzy land all right
维尔或模糊的土地都可以
they'll often say to you well you know
他们经常会对你说 你知道的
I'll say to them no I don't know well
我会对他们说不，我不知道
you know no no I don't know well you
你知道不，我不了解你
know what I mean no I don't know what
知道我的意思不，我不知道是什么
you mean tell me what you mean that kind
你的意思是告诉我你是什么意思的那种
of exchange is going on all the time
交换正在进行中
because I want to know exactly what they
因为我想确切地知道他们是什么
mean that's oftentimes an avoidance
意味着通常是一种避免
I don't want to have to talk about that
我不想谈论这个
so I just say you know that's a general
所以我只是说你知道这是一般的
area and as you're doing that you've got
区域和你正在做的那样
to be very careful to withhold judgment
要非常小心地拒绝判断
until you've heard the whole story go
直到你听到整个故事去
back to proverbs chapter 18 we took a
回到谚语第18章我们拿了一个
look at that passage earlier but later
看那个通道较早，但后来
on it talks about the first to plead his
在它谈论第一个辩护他的
case seems right until another comes
案件似乎正确，直到另一个来
along and examines them I mean there are
沿着并检查他们我的意思是有
many times that that's happened in
很多时候，这种情况发生在
ministry over the past thirty years of
在过去三十年的事工
counseling I've had a wife come into
咨询我有一个妻子进来
counseling and she's described what's
咨询，她描述了什么
going on in her marriage and at the end
继续她的婚姻和最后
of that counseling session I thought
那个咨询会议我想
that her husband was the worst man that
她的丈夫是那个最糟糕的人
ever walked the planet then the husband
曾经走过这个星球然后是丈夫
came in and he told me his side of the
进来了，他告诉我他的侧
issue I'm going whoa wait a minute
问题我要等一会儿
that's a whole different picture over
那是完全不同的画面
the same episodes here I'm ready to
同样的剧集在这里我已经准备好了
judge that man and send him to hell
判断那个男人并把他送到地狱
alright now I get a little bit more of a
好吧，现在我得到多一点的
balanced view of what's going on
这是怎么回事的平衡的观点
okay so withhold judgment until you're
好吧所以保留判断直到你
able to hear both sides of the story
能听到 这个故事的两面
that has gotten me out of a lot of very
这已经得到了我很多的非常的
tricky situations remembering that
记住这一点的棘手情况
little truth this is wise even in
即使在这方面，这也是明智的
business when you have a problem with
业务，当你有一个问题
co-workers on the job and you're only
在工作的同事，你只是
hearing one side of the issue you get
听到你得到的问题的一面
this distorted view or you you begin to
这种扭曲的观点，或者你开始
form a bad attitude about the person
对这个人形成一种恶劣的态度
that they're talking about when you're
他们在谈论你的时候
not listening to the other side of that
不听那个的另一面
issue you've got to listen to the other
问题你必须听另一个
side of the issue now I got to agree
问题的一面，我现在同意了
with you if you're a lazy councillor
和你一起，如果你是一个懒惰的议员
you're only gonna listen to one side
你只会倾听一方
because sometimes when you hear both
因为有时候你都听到了
sides it's very confusing you go oh this
你知道这一点非常令人困惑哦
is so hard I don't know what to believe
很难，我不知道该相信什么
they say this and the other person says
他们说这个和另一个人说
this and then but if you're going to be
这个然后但如果你要成为
fair in your judgement you have to do
你必须做到公平
that if you're gonna be righteous in
如果你要成为正义的话
your judgments you're gonna have to do
你的判断，你将要做的
that you say wait a minute
你说等一下
doesn't the Bible say you're not
圣经不是说你不是
supposed to judge and then one Matthew 7
应该判断一个马太福音7章
says don't judge lest ye be judged
说不要判断，以免受到审判
no that's not what it says I mean that's
不，这不是它说的我的意思是
the words that it says but if you read
它说的话， 但如果你读
it within context that's the log in the
它是在上下文中的日志
splinter right in the eye in other words
换句话说就是在眼睛里分裂
don't go around trying to pick splinters
不要随随便便试图 挑选碎片
out of other people's eyes actually the
从其他人的眼睛其实
Greek term there is particle it's like
希腊语中有粒子就像它一样
we would say today floaties you ever
我们会说今天你会漂浮
have a floaties in your eye yeah you
你眼中有漂浮物， 是的
know a little floaty little piece of
知道一点浮动的小块
dust what if I came up to you and said
如果我走到你面前说什么呢
hey I see that floaties let me take that
嘿， 我看到漂浮物让我接受了
out of your eye you go whoa whoa and all
从你的眼睛里，你去哇哇哇哇大笑
along there's a little gigantic log
沿途有一个巨大的日志
hanging out of my eye all right Jesus
我的眼睛一直挂在耶稣身上
wasn't saying you can't judge the people
不是说你不能判断人
he's saying you can't judge other people
他说你不能判断别人
with a standard you first don't you use
与标准你先不要使用
upon your own life so you got to be
在你自己的生活中，你必须成为
stricter and judging yourself than other
比其他人更严格和判断自己
people Bible doesn't say you can't judge
人们圣经不说你无法判断
says you've got to be strict at judging
说你必须严格审判
yourself before you judge other people
在你判断别人之前你自己
and use a more refined judgement on
并使用更精确的判断
yourself than you do with other people
你自己比你和别人一样
so you've got it withhold judgment and
所以你得到了它的判断力
then mark important areas for further
然后标记重要区域以进一步
questioning
疑问
record patterns significant statements
记录模式的重要陈述
habits observe their countenance
习惯观察他们的面容
sometimes we refer to that as the halo
有时，我们指的是作为晕
data communication secular call it
数据通信世俗称之为
nonverbal communication I like halo data
非语言交流我喜欢光环数据
all right what's their halo data what's
好吧，他们的光环数据是什么
their their attitude about this thing or
他们对这件事或他们的态度
their attitude about particular people
他们对特定人的态度
what is it what's going on it's
究竟是什么 发生了什么事情是
interesting they're in Genesis chapter 4
有趣的是他们在创世纪第4章
it describes Cain it says that he was
它描述该隐它说他是
angry and his face was downcast as
气得变了脸 色为
away.the the English translates that the
离开。英语翻译了
Hebrew actually talks about the fact
希伯来语实际上谈到了这个事实
that his his face sagged he was
他的脸上下垂他
depressed
郁闷
his countenance his face sagged you ever
他的脸上露出了你的脸
seen a bulldog all right people are
看到一个牛头犬没事人
really depressed their face sags
真的很郁闷他们的脸凹陷
so observe countenance nonverbal
所以观察非语言的面容
communication is the halo data and be
沟通是光环数据而已
careful because sometimes nonverbal
小心， 因为有时非语言
communication listen to me can be
沟通听我说都可以
misread easily misread for example this
误读容易误读，例如这个
is how the Queen of England expresses
英格兰女王是如何表达的
her emotions
她的情绪
sad happy dis rot hilarious outrage
伤心的快乐腐烂热闹的愤怒
somber jovial and grief-stricken alright
忧郁的快活和悲伤的好吧
so be very very careful on how you're
所以要非常小心你的方式
reading nonverbals okay there are other
阅读nonverbals好吧还有其他
methods as well
方法也是如此
information from other people giving
来自其他人的信息
your counsel your perspective and
你的建议你的观点和
inviting their feedback observation of
邀请他们反馈观察
the council the outside of this session
理事会在本届会议之外
recording conversations at home
在家里录制对话
that's very nice now I'm grateful we
现在非常好，我很感激我们
live in the day and age that we do
生活在我们所做的日子和年龄
sometimes I'll instruct a couple to have
有时我会指示一对夫妇
a conference table at home and I'll tell
在家里的会议桌，我会告诉你
them exactly how to do a family
他们究竟该如何做一个家庭
conference table and I want them to set
会议桌，我希望他们设置
up the family DVD recorder I want to see
我希望看到的家庭DVD录像机
it alright and bring in the recording
没关系，带上录音
the next counseling session I want to
我想要的下一次咨询会议
see what goes on so at first they're
看看发生了什么，所以起初他们是
really awkward sitting talking to each
真的很尴尬坐着跟每个人说话
other in front and pretty soon doesn't
在前面的其他很快就没有了
take long they forget about the camera
他们想忘了相机
all right now they're into their
现在好了 ，他们是到他们
exchange recording those conversations
交换录制这些对话
at home and then I can play them back
在家里，然后我可以回放它们
and show them on my computer I say okay
并在我的电脑上显示它们我说好的
now look their conversations going along
现在看他们的谈话一直在进行
great right here but look what what
很棒，但看看是什么
sabotages conversation see that comment
破坏对话看到评论
now I see you doing that frequently in
现在我看到你这样做，经常在
your communication with one another that
你与他人的沟通
sabotages the communication listen to
破坏沟通的听力
their prayers their prayers tell you
他们祈祷他们的祈祷告诉你
what they really want get them to pray
他们真正想要的是让他们祈祷
that's good data gathering what's going
这是收集正在发生的事情的好数据
on in their prayers and then dad are
在他们的祈祷，然后爸爸
gathering homework giving them homework
收集作业给他们做作业
that solicits some kind of input that
该征求某种输入的那
gives you good data now I'm not going to
为您提供了很好的数据，现在我不打算
spend a long time on this but let me
花了很长时间，但让我
stress the importance of listening
强调倾听的重要性
carefully well what are we talking about
我们在谈论什么
well in proverbs chapter 20 and verse 25
谚语第20章和第25节
it says is a trap for a man to say it is
它说的是一个人说，这是一个陷阱
holy
圣
and after the vows to make inquiry in
和许愿之后才在询价
other words you've got to listen
换句话说你必须听
carefully rather than being rash to make
小心而不是轻率地做
a statement listen sometimes requires a
声明听有时需要一个
lot of self-control on your part and now
你和你现在的很多自我控制
what are we talking about listen for
我们在谈论什么是倾听
stuff like blame shifting that was
像责备转移那样的东西
something that's started by Adam and Eve
亚当和夏娃开始的事情
when God came to Eve and said what is
当上帝来到夏娃并说什么是
this you have done she or to Adam what
你已经完成了她或亚当做了什么
is this you have done Adam said don't
这是你做过亚当说的不做
look at me it's that woman you created
看着我，那是你创造的那个女人
and then he turns to Eve and Eve says
然后他转向夏娃和夏娃说
don't look at me it's a serpent you
别看我，这是一条蛇
created the passed the buck game was
创造了传递的巴克游戏
invented way back when sin came into the
当罪进入时，发明了一种方式
world we just have more sophisticated
世界我们只是更精致
ways of doing it or listen for words
这样做或听单词的方式
like Kant unable to too much is that
像康德无法过多的是，
that you really can't or you won't
你真的不能或你不会
what is it you can't or you won't listen
什么是你不能或你不会听
for the victim mentality I'm just the
对于受害者的心态我只是
victim of what everybody does to me the
每个人对我做的事的受害者
way that they treat me I'm just a blob
他们对待我的方式我只是一个blob
of emotions being affected by what
情绪会受到什么影响
everybody else does victim mentality
其他人都有受害者的心态
listen when they try to call sin
当他们试图称罪时听
sickness they'll do that quite
他们会这样做的
frequently listen for rabbit trails
经常听兔子踪迹
people will take you on rabbit trails or
人们会带你去兔子小径或
some people who will go around the barn
有些人会绕过谷仓
15 times before entering the barn okay
进入谷仓之前好15次
we've been around that barn let's get
我们一直在那个谷仓让我们得到
inside the barn rabbit trails listen to
在谷仓兔子小径里面听
what your counsel he doesn't say what
你的忠告他没有说什么
are they not talking about they talk
他们不是在谈论他们说话吗？
about everybody in the family but
关于家庭中的每个人但是
so-and-so
谁谁
sometimes that's some of the most
有时这是最多的一些
fruitful data gathering is who they're
富有成效的数据收集就是他们的身份
not talking about listen for
不是在谈论
hopelessness hopelessness a lot of
无望无望很多
counseling he's come in hope
咨询他是有希望的
they've tried everything that they
他们已经尝试了一切，他们
thought in order to resolve this problem
以为要解决这个问题
and now they're coming to you because
现在他们来找你了，因为
well last resort maybe you might be able
也许你可能会做到最后
to help but I'm pretty sure you won't be
帮助 ， 但我敢肯定你会不会
able to I love those kind of counseling
能够我喜欢那种辅导
appointments cuz I know it's not me
约会因为我知道这不是我
and I'll agree with them I say you're
我会同意他们的观点我说你
right I cannot help you a bit but God
对，但我不能帮助你，但上帝
can
能够
God can listen for evasive Ness people
上帝可以聆听回避的尼斯人
are very evasive usually in the areas
通常在这些地区非常回避
that they're evasive about that's the
他们对这就是回避
real issue that's going to give you a
真正的问题会给你一个
significant amount of information listen
大量的信息听
for exaggerations exaggerations often
夸张夸张经常
are just lies they exaggerate listen for
只是谎言他们夸大地倾听
defensiveness what are they being
防守是什么
defensive about or judging another
防守或判断另一个人
person's motives or their willingness to
人的动机或他们的意愿
accept responsibility now there's some
现在承担责任有一些
listening habits to avoid as well
收听习惯，以避免以及
don't interrupt your counsel ly because
不要打断你的忠告，因为
they're learning from what you're
他们是从你学习什么
modeling don't jump to conclusions about
建模不要妄下结论
things don't be quick to make quick
事情并不快捷
judgments think about it carefully don't
判断想想小心不要
let your mind wander
让你的思绪徘徊
some people can drone on and on ad
有些人可以在广告上无人机
infinitum ad nauseam they can the best
无限的， 令人作呕他们可以做到最好
wording counseling by the way the best
措辞辅导最好的方式
word in counseling I learned this from
在咨询中我从中学到了这一点
Jay Adams is whoa whoa that means stop
杰伊亚当斯是谁，谁意味着停止
all right
好吧
that's the best word in counseling whoa
这是咨询中最好的词哇
let's stop right there now I've been
我现在就在 那里停下 来
listening to you for the last two hours
在过去的两个小时里听你说
it's time that you listen to what God
它是你聆听神的时间
says so don't let your mind wander when
这么说不要让你的思绪徘徊
they do this kind of things don't do
他们做这种事情不做
distracting things you know like
分散你知道的事情
to your fingernails or I used to be able
到你的指甲或我曾经能够
to do that I can't do it anymore
要做到这一点我不能再这样做了
crack your knuckles don't do distracting
破解你的指关节不要分散注意力
things don't allow the person to waste
事情不允许这个人浪费
time either because they know that
时间或者是因为他们知道，
they're wasting time and the chances of
他们浪费时间和机会
them coming back for counseling with you
他们 回来跟你辅导
is probably pretty remote if they know
如果他们知道的话可能很遥远
that they can manage the hour that that
他们可以管理那个小时
way don't hesitate to ask if you don't
如果你不这样做，请不要犹豫
understand don't hesitate to ask now all
明白不要犹豫，现在问一切
of that is important data gathering let
这是重要的数据收集让
me talk a little bit about interpreting
我说一下关于如何解释
the data understanding and discerning
数据的理解和辨别
what's going on with the problem now
现在这个问题发生了什么
there are a lot of illustrations of this
这里有很多插图
you can see it in First Samuel chapter 1
你可以在First Samuel第1章中看到它
verses 12 through 18 with Eli and Hannah
Eli和Hannah的第12到18节
interpreting the data mark chapter 6
解释数据标记第6章
verses 45 through 50 to the disciples
45至50节给门徒
fearful yet their heart is hard in mark
可怕但他们的心脏是很难的标志
chapter 10 the rich young ruler what
第10章富裕的年轻统治者是什么
shall I do to inherit eternal life Jesus
我该怎样做才能继承耶稣的永生
read behind it what was really going on
在它后面读到真正发生的事情
in that man's life Mary and Martha what
在那个男人的生活玛丽和玛莎什么的
their priorities are when Jesus came to
他们的重点是耶稣来到
visit 2nd Timothy 4:10 demas deserted he
参观提摩太后书4:10德马斯冷清他
loved this present age Paul said 3rd
喜欢这个时代保罗说第3
John 9 and 10 Diotrephes who was
John 9和10 Diotrephes是谁
supposed to be a protector of the church
应该是教会的保护者
but in reality was actually doing the
但在现实中，实际上做
church much harm and you can see a good
教会伤害很大，你可以看到一个好的
illustration of that with the case study
与案例研究的插图
of gus-gus thinks that his particular
gus-gus认为他的特殊
problem has to do with his self-love and
问题与他的自我爱 做的 ，
self-esteem and I just don't have enough
自尊，我只是没有足够的
self-esteem I don't have enough ego
自尊我没有足够的自负
strength to be able to do what I need to
力量能够做我需要的
do Gus thinks and so I'm here for
做格斯认为，所以我在这里
counseling for you to give me the ego
建议你给我自我
strength that I need and we learn in our
我需要的力量， 我们 在我们的学习
earlier counseling sessions that that's
那些早期的咨询会议
not training sessions we learned that
不是我们学到的培训课程
that's not the problem that's not the
这不是问题，不是
problem at all
问题就在于此
Gus is way too self focused that's the
格斯太专注于自我
problem
问题
you can read that case study in your
你可以阅读你的案例研究
notes now what's the process that we're
现在注意到我们的过程是什么
dealing with well take data and
处理好数据和
prayerfully compare what is going on
虔诚地比较正在发生的事情
with God's Word that's really key
用上帝的话来说这是非常关键的
compare the person's behavioral
比较一下这个人的行为
responses compare the person's thoughts
回答比较了这个人的想法
attitudes and interpretations and then
态度和解释然后
compare the person's desires and values
比较人的欲望和价值观
and expectations all of this these
并期望所有这些
things are vitally vitally important
事情至关重要
when it comes to interpreting good data
当谈到解释好的数据时
you've got to think through what they
你必须仔细思考他们
are giving you think through what they
正在给你思考他们
are giving you and then then take the
正在给你，然后拿走
data and look for themes are there
数据和寻找的主题是有
typical behavioral responses in certain
特定的典型行为反应
situations do you see them behaving the
情况你看到他们的表现吗？
same way in similar situations that
同样的情况也是如此
they've given you that are part of the
他们已经赐给你了属于你的一部分
past are there typical thoughts
过去有典型的想法
attitudes or interpretations are there
那里有态度或解释
typical expectations desires longings or
典型的期望渴望渴望或
demands that the person has in certain
要求这个人有一定的
situations and then you need to take
情况，然后你需要采取
that data and make sure that you are
那些数据并确保你是
labeling and describing the problem in a
标记和描述问题
biblical way use biblical words and
圣经的方式使用圣经的话和
categories when a person says to you
一个人对你说的类别
well I think that I am struggling with
嗯，我想，我挣扎
an anxiety disorder well the Bible says
焦虑症以及圣经 说
that you're anxious no I have a phobia
你是急人无我有恐惧症
none of the Bible says you're fearful
没有一本圣经说你很害怕
they want to they want the way that you
他们希望他们想要你的方式
label things suggests the remedies so if
标签的东西建议补救措施，如果
you're going to label them with a
你打算用它来标记它们
psychotropic label then the remedy
精神标签然后补救措施
oftentimes is medication or at least
通常是药物或至少
lifelong therapy here in the LA area
洛杉矶地区的终身疗法
Hollywood half of Hollywood thrives on
好莱坞一半的好莱坞茁壮成长
psycho therapists working with movie
与电影合作的心理治疗师
stars spending millions and millions of
明星花费了数百万美元
dollars in lifelong therapy and never
终身治疗的美元，永远不会
getting anything resolved
得到解决的东西
paster I know it's wrong but I have been
贴纸我知道这是错的，但我一直都是
guilty of buying over $100 a week worth
每周购买超过100美元的价值
of lottery tickets for the past five
过去五年的彩票
years
年份
I need help well pastor thinks to
牧师认为我需要帮助
himself does he have a gambling
他自己也有赌博
addiction is it obsessive compulsive
成瘾是强迫症
disorder what terminology would the
无序是什么术语
Bible use about this really becomes an
关于这一点的圣经使用真的变成了
essential issue of dissatisfaction with
不满的基本问题
life and a greed issue of the heart
生活和内心的贪婪问题
never forget I had a man like this
忘不了有一个人这样
several years ago he and his wife came
几年前他和他的妻子来了
for marriage counseling but hidden
对于婚姻咨询，但隐藏
underneath the surface eventually during
最终在表面之下
the counseling he revealed that they
他透露了他们的咨询
were $30,000 in debt because every week
因为每周都有30,000美元的债务
he bought lottery tickets he was hoping
他买了他希望的彩票
to strike it rich I'll never forget his
要发财致富，我永远不会忘记他的
wife had no idea this was going on her
妻子不知道这是在发生在她身上
breaking into tears during that
在那期间泪流满面
particular counseling session and the
特别是咨询会和
hopelessness was written all over her
在她身上写满了绝望
face and he repented praise God we got
面对，他忏悔赞美我们得到的上帝
them on a system whereby they began to
他们在一个他们开始的系统上
pay back their debts and pay off all
偿还债务并还清所有债务
their credit cards which were just maxed
他们的信用卡只是最大限度的
out no wonder they were having problems
难怪他们遇到了问题
in their marriage because he had this
在他们的婚姻中，因为他有这个
whole hidden area of his life six months
整个隐藏的生活区域 六个月
after they graduated a counseling they
他们毕业后给他们提供咨询
were paying back all those debts he gave
正在偿还他给的所有债务
me a call and he said you know my
我打个电话，他说你认识我
six-year-old son was diagnosed with a
六岁的儿子被诊断为
brain tumor and all I keep thinking he
脑肿瘤，我一直在想他
said to me was how far $30,000 would go
对我说是30,000美元会走多远
to help him so you need to avoid
帮助他，所以你需要避免
psychological labels avoid them use
心理标签避免使用它们
biblical terms an alcoholic is not an
圣经术语一个酒鬼不是
alcoholic biblically that person is a
这个人是圣经的圣经
drunkard fudging the truth that's lying
醉汉捏造谎言的真相
ask your counselor what they mean when
问你的辅导员他们的意思时
they use non biblical psychological
他们使用非圣经的心理
labels for example what do you mean when
标签例如你什么意思
you use that term what are you avoiding
你使用那个术语你会避免什么
what are you desiring what are you
你还想要什么？
thinking why are you thinking that way
想着你为什么有这样的想法
what is motivating you to think those
是什么激励你去思考这些
thoughts
思念
like personality disorder codependency
喜欢人格障碍的依赖性
by the way codependency from a biblical
从圣经相互依赖的方式
standpoint is nothing but fear of man
立场只不过是对人类的恐惧
it's fear man and by the way as soon as
它是恐惧男人，顺便说一句
you start using biblical labels then the
你开始使用圣经标签了
Bible opens up to you it opens up as an
圣经打开了你，它打开了
answer book well the Bible talks about
圣经谈到的答案书
for your man in several different places
为你的男人在几个不同的地方
dysfunctional family schizophrenia
功能失调的家庭精神分裂症
schizophrenia is just a nice Greek word
精神分裂症只是一个很好的希腊词
of people who believe that they have
那些相信自己拥有的人
personalities talking in the back of
个性在后面说话
their their head actually working with
他们的头竟与合作
schizophrenia it's not not hard at all
精神分裂症并不难
if this represented all the
如果这代表所有的
schizophrenics in the world only this
精神分裂症在世界上只有这一点
many are really genuine true Christians
许多人都是真正真正的基督徒
and of those people you have to settle
而那些你需要解决的人
one thing early who's going to define
有一件事早就要定义了
your reality for you
你的现实
the voices in the back of your head or
你脑后的声音
the Bible what God's Word says if you
圣经，如果你是神的话语
can settle that issue early with this
能早日解决这个问题
you can't work with all these other
你无法与其他所有人合作
people a lot of schizophrenia think that
人们很多精神分裂症都认为
their Christian they're not but you'd
他们的基督徒他们不是，但你
only work with a Christian remember all
只与基督徒一起工作，记住一切
counseling is pre counseling until a
咨询是预先咨询，直到
person comes to Christ right all right
人正好来到基督面前
well if you can settle that issue early
好吧，如果你能尽早解决这个问题
who defines your reality for you is that
谁定义了你的现实你的是，
what God's Word says or is that voice
上帝的话语是什么，或者是那个声音
the back of your head that says hurt
你的头后面说伤了
yourself or hurt that other person
自己或伤害他人
damaged emotions low self-esteem all
受损的情绪低自尊
these are psychological unmet needs
这些是心理上未满足的需求
perfectionism workaholism mental illness
完美主义工作狂精神疾病
addictions multiple personalities eating
成瘾多个人吃
disorders all of these are issues that
所有这些都是紊乱的问题
go back to what the Bible says they have
回到圣经所说的话
biblical labels that we can put on them
我们可以放在他们身上的圣经标签
then take the data and then put it on
然后获取数据，然后将其打开
the witness stand what what are the
在证人席上什么什么是
biblical categories could be used to
圣经类别可以用来
describe that person I'm counseling what
描述了人，我什么辅导
does the person understand about
这个人是否理解
biblical change
圣经的改变
what about complicating factors what is
什么是复杂的因素是什么
the best way to approach accounts Lee
接近李某账户的最佳方式
what does the counsel these greatest
这些忠告的忠告是什么？
need what does the data indicate about
需要数据表明的内容
why am i counseled he is not resolved
为什么我劝他他没有得到解决
upon this is a great list to go through
在这是一个伟大的名单要经过
when you're counseling someone what is
当你咨询的人是什么
the reason the counsel he has come for
是他来的律师的原因
help at this particular time what does
在这个特定的时间帮助做什么
the counts
计数
we expect out of the counseling what
我们期待从咨询中得到什么
does the data indicate about the
数据是否表明了
possible organic factors remember you do
可能的有机因素记得你
not practice medicine or law unless you
除非你，否则不要练习医学或法律
happen to be a medical doctor or a
碰巧是医生或
lawyer you don't do that so don't try to
律师， 你不这样做，所以不要试图
practice medicine I know you may believe
练习医学我知道你可能相信
in all your evil remedies but don't take
在你所有的邪恶补救措施，但不要采取
anybody any of your counsel ease off of
你的任何一个律师都放松了
Medicine you got an ethical problem when
医学你什么时候有道德问题
you do that kind of thing you send them
你做那种事你给他们
back to their medical doctor to do that
回到他们的医生那里去做
not to mention the fact that you don't
更不用说你不这样做 的事实
know the side effects are coming off
知道副作用正在消失
medications it's not your job I rarely
药物这不是你的工作我很少
make medications at issue I rarely ever
我很少做药物问题
do that I just present what the Word of
那样做我只是提出了什么
God says intervention they make council
上帝说干涉他们会成为理事会
he says you know what I don't think I
他说你知道我不认为我
need these psychotropic drugs so well
这些精神药物需要这么好
we're fine go back to your doctor and
我们很好， 回到你的医生那里
say do you want to be put on some kind
说你想要某种形式
of decreasing dosage and then we'll work
的减少量，然后我们会工作
with you with all the emotions that will
用你所有的情绪是会
come swirling back like a tsunami will
像海啸那样旋转回来
work with you and how to respond to them
与您合作以及如何回应他们
from a biblical perspective fine that's
从圣经的角度来看很好
good I don't even make it an issue take
好， 我甚至没有把它作为一个问题
the data and perfectly study and
数据和完美的研究和
identify what may be going on in the
确定哪些可以在被回事
person's heart is that the lust of the
人的心是那种欲望
flesh is that the lust of eyes is the
肉体是眼睛的欲望
pride of life
生命的骄傲
what kind of idolatry is there what is
什么样的偶像崇拜有什么
it that they're really bowing down to
他们真的很鞠躬
more than anything else
最重要的是
what are they bowing down to find out
什么是他们鞠躬发现
what they're worshipping these self-made
他们正在崇拜这些自制的东西
gods those become the ruling motives of
众神那些成为统治者的动机
their life and then begin to formulate
他们的生活然后开始制定
interpretations the nature and cause of
解释的性质和原因
that person's problems use scripture to
那个人的问题使用经文
identify the different possibilities is
确定不同的可能性是
it lying
它说谎
is it being critical is it depression is
抑郁是至关重要的
it anxiety is it fear is it difficulty
它的焦虑是恐惧是困难
handling trials is it bizarre or weird
处理试验是奇怪或奇怪的
behavior why are they manifesting that
行为为什么他们表现出来
particular behavior what does the Bible
特别的行为是什么圣经
say about it
说出来
you can use your own experience here in
你可以在这里使用自己的经验
counseling but you got to be careful
咨询， 但你必须小心
here
这里
proverbs 1410 the heart knows its own
谚语1410心里知道自己
bitterness and a stranger does not share
苦涩和陌生人不分享
its joy 1st Corinthians 10:13 no
它的喜乐哥林多前书10:13没有
temptation has taken you except for what
除了什么，诱惑已经带走了你
is common to man and God is faithful he
人是常见的，上帝是忠诚的
will not allow you to be tempted beyond
不会让你动心超越
what you are able but with that
你有什么能力，但随之而来
temptation you will provide a way of
诱惑你会提供一种方式
escape so that you may be able to endure
逃避， 以便你可以忍受
it and then use your experience with
它然后用你的经验
other people but be careful here you
其他人但请小心你
have to exercise a biblical form of
必须运用圣经的形式
confidence you don't use the experience
你不相信经验
unless you ask of another person unless
除非你问另一个人，除非
you ask their permission to do so test
你要求他们允许这样做测试
the validity of your tentative
你试探性的有效性
interpretations review the data to see
解释审查数据看
which passo possibilities have the least
哪种可能性最小
or the most support pray again continue
或者最大的支持再次祈祷继续
to seek more information seek input from
寻求更多信息寻求意见
another counselor and then explain your
另一位顾问，然后解释你的
interpretation to your counseling and
解释你的咨询和
then ask for feedback I'm doing that all
然后请求反馈我正在做这一切
the time test your interpretations
时间测试你的解释
carefully alright
小心好
test your interpretations carefully
仔细测试你的解释
there's Midvale school for the gifted
有天才的Midvale学校
you'll wake up in the middle of night
你会在半夜醒来
and get that having tested and proving
并得到测试和证明
the validity of their of your
他们的有效性
interpretation and go on to formulate a
解释并继续制定一个
strategy for helping the person overcome
策略帮助克服人
problems that includes clarifying the
问题包括澄清
issues with which you deal with includes
您处理的问题包括
prioritizing the order in which you will
优先考虑您的订单
deal with those issues and includes
处理这些问题并包括在内
deciding the manner and the method that
决定方式和方法
you will use in providing help to this
您将在此提供帮助使用
person now there's a lot more we could
那个人现在有更多我们可以做的
say about that but we don't have enough
说到这一点，但我们没有足够的
time to do so
时间这样做
you
您